

#### CONTACT ME AT

- alrobwilloliver@gmail.com
- www.alanoliver.dev
  www.github.com/alrobwilloliver
- www.linkedin.com/in/alan oliver-3a28aa118/

# SKILLS SUMMARY

- Full Stack Development
- Node JS
- Go
- Git
- TypeScript
- Agile Development
- MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB
- Heroku, AWS
- Test Driven Development
- Linux

## AWARDS RECEIVED

- Outstanding Student Awards British Council Mandarin
  Scholarship Spring and
  Summer Semesters (2018)
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold Award (2016)
- Year Group Best English Student (2016)

# **ALAN OLIVER**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a software engineer with 3 years experience.
I am passionate about creating products that solve customer problems, enthusiastic to share knowledge and ideas, like to learn quickly and adapt when facing new challenges and I am proactive about looking for ways to improve processes or code.

I am also passionate about Test Driven Development, with experience maintaining and updating a testing suite for SQL queries in Docker and API endpoints in a recent role. One recent achievement in my role was fully testing and fixing bugs in a billing system in native Go tests and updating database values from float64 to a more precise decimal library completely independently.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Delivery Consultant**

Global Logic | August 2022 - Present

- Deliver client projects in quality code
- To ensure I am continually up skilling in in-demand technologies
- Conduct bi-weekly discussion and research presentations for the development capability.

# Software Engineer

Cudo Ventures | March 2021 - August 2022

- Develop new features on and maintain existing RESTful and gRPC API.
- Contribute to backend microservice infrastructure in Golang and Node.js.
- Implement, update and maintain tests for software to ensure reliability.
- Implement front end features in TypeScript VueJS

## Junior Developer

New Verve Consulting | August 2020 - March 2021

- Develop user focused frontend features for an Atlassian Marketplace app in React JS.
- Implement tests for software to ensure reliability.

# EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

#### Online Courses

March 2021 - June 2022

- Test With Go Jon Calhoun
- gRPC [Golang] Master Class: Build Modern API & Microservices Stephane Marek
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp 2023 Jonas Schmodtmann
- Backend Master Class [Golang + Postgres + Kubernetes + gRPC] Tech School
- Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations and More! Jonas Schmedtmann

#### LeWagon FullStack Coding Bootcamp

Chengdu, China | June 2019 - September 2019

- HTML, JavaScript, CSS
- Git, Heroku, APIs, command line
- MySQL, MVC architecture